

901.603.1764

stephawiggins@gmail.com

stephaniewiggins.me

wigginsstephanie

Memphis, TN

About

With graphic design, marketing, and web development skills, I weave my expertise triad with a project's initiatives to create a user-centric, cohesive experience.

Skills

Development

HTML & CSS/SCSS | JavaScript/ReactJS Ruby on Rails | Git/GitHub | Gatsby Bootstrap | Wordpress

Other Software & Skills

Sketch | XD | Figma | Invision InDesign | Illustrator | Photoshop Salesforce (Admin) SEO: Moz | SEMrush | Google Analytics Email Marketing: Mailchimp | Salesforce Marketing Cloud Social Media: BuzzSumo | Hootsuite

Professional Experience

ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S RESEARCH HOSPITAL | Memphis, Tennessee Associate Software Development Engineer July 2019 – Present

- Design and develop the Genomics Platform app on St. Jude Cloud, a ReactJS/Ruby on Rails site that shares genomics data and analysis tools with scientists globally
- Design and develop an educational Gatsby site and corresponding figures
- Worked with a network of internal and external professionals to launch the site's restructure and spearheaded developing the new, top-level Gatsby site
- Designed and maintain an electronic data access agreement wizard that integrates with DocuSign® and improves the UX of requesting data from the app
- Expanded the wizard's functionality to pre-populate users' information in data access agreements for users to collect signatures manually (alternative to DocuSign®)
- Worked with another designer to rebuild the project's theme repo, enhancing its content to empower internal stakeholders and developers to harvest brand assets and use the theme's components on their sites

MERCER CAPITAL | Memphis, Tennessee Senior Graphic Designer & Marketing Associate July 2014 – July 2019

- · Protected the brand in both print and digital mediums and oversaw marketing data
- Regularly updated corporate website, redesigned the CEO's blog, and maintained several microsites
- Created more than a dozen quarterly newsletters, mocked up several weekly blogs, and communicated with corresponding email distribution lists
- · Analyzed SEO and traffic stats on websites, emails, and social media
- Oversaw the Salesforce build-out and became in-house Salesforce admin

FIRST STATE | Martin, Tennessee Graphic Artist & Marketing Assistant

October 2013 - April 2014

- · Created cohesive designs for a diversified financial institution within regulations
- · Created print ads for newspapers, lobby posters, and fliers
- Translated print ads to digital ecosystem for emails and website graphics

SOUTHERN BRIDE MAGAZINE | Memphis, Tennessee Graphic Design & Marketing Intern

June 2012 - August 2012

- · Created website and social ads for clients and buttons for sister site
- Vetted vendors to feature products and as potential advertising partners

Education

TECHNICAL TRAINING | Tech901

Web Programming | Spring 2019 Coding I.0 (Harvard's CS50) | Spring 2018

UNDERGRADUATE | University of Tennessee at Martin

B.F.A. Graphic Design, Summa Cum Laude, GPA 4.0 | May 2014